<add allowDups="false"><doc><field name="LayerId">AverageAnnualGroundwaterRecharge</field><field name="Name">AverageAnnualGroundwaterRecharge</field><field name="CollectionId">initial collection</field><field name="Institution">Minnesota</field><field name="InstitutionSort">Minnesota</field><field name="Access">Public</field><field name="DataType">Undefined</field><field name="DataTypeSort">Undefined</field><field name="Availability">Online</field><field name="LayerDisplayName">Average Annual Recharge - Twin Cities Metropolitan Area, Minnesota</field><field name="LayerDisplayNameSort">Average Annual Recharge - Twin Cities Metropolitan Area, Minnesota</field><field name="Publisher">Metropolitan Council</field><field name="PublisherSort">Metropolitan Council</field><field name="Originator">Barr Engineering Company</field><field name="OriginatorSort">Barr Engineering Company</field><field name="ThemeKeywords">None</field><field name="PlaceKeywords">None</field><field name="Abstract">This dataset contains long-term average (1975-2003) annual recharge estimates for the seven-county Twin Cities metropolitan area. Values are in inches per year. Recharge was estimated using a daily soil-water balance (SWB) model developed by the Wisconsin Geological and Natural History Survey in conjuction with a regional groundwater flow model developed for the Twin Cities metropolitan area. This dataset was developed by Barr Engineering Company for the Metropolitan Council to support the development of the Twin Cities metropolitan area regional groundwater flow model (Metro Model 2).

More information about this process is provided in the 2009 Metropolitan Council report 'Twin Cities Metropolitan Area Regional Groundwater Flow Model Version 2.00 - Technical Report in Support of the Metropolitan Area Master Water Supply Plan', which is available online at www.metrocouncil.org/environment/WaterSupply/metrogroundwatermodeldatasets.htm.</field><field name="MaxY">5029183.7912165</field><field name="MinY">4924223.7912165</field><field name="MinX">-419964.72034215</field><field name="MaxX">-521644.72034215</field><field name="ContentDate">2009-03-26T00:00:00Z</field><field name="Location">{"download": "ftp://gisftp.metc.state.mn.us/Recharge.zip"}</field><field name="WorkspaceName" /><field name="FgdcText">&lt;?xml version="1.0"?&gt;&lt;metadata&gt;
	&lt;idinfo&gt;
		&lt;citation&gt;
			&lt;citeinfo&gt;
				&lt;title&gt;Average Annual Recharge - Twin Cities Metropolitan Area, Minnesota&lt;/title&gt;
				&lt;origin&gt;Barr Engineering Company&lt;/origin&gt;
				&lt;pubinfo&gt;
					&lt;publish&gt;Metropolitan Council&lt;/publish&gt;
				&lt;/pubinfo&gt;
				&lt;pubdate&gt;Unpublished material&lt;/pubdate&gt;
				&lt;onlink&gt;ftp://gisftp.metc.state.mn.us/Recharge.zip&lt;/onlink&gt;
			&lt;/citeinfo&gt;
		&lt;/citation&gt;
		&lt;descript&gt;
			&lt;abstract&gt;This dataset contains long-term average (1975-2003) annual recharge estimates for the seven-county Twin Cities metropolitan area. Values are in inches per year. Recharge was estimated using a daily soil-water balance (SWB) model developed by the Wisconsin Geological and Natural History Survey in conjuction with a regional groundwater flow model developed for the Twin Cities metropolitan area. This dataset was developed by Barr Engineering Company for the Metropolitan Council to support the development of the Twin Cities metropolitan area regional groundwater flow model (Metro Model 2).

More information about this process is provided in the 2009 Metropolitan Council report 'Twin Cities Metropolitan Area Regional Groundwater Flow Model Version 2.00 - Technical Report in Support of the Metropolitan Area Master Water Supply Plan', which is available online at www.metrocouncil.org/environment/WaterSupply/metrogroundwatermodeldatasets.htm.&lt;/abstract&gt;
			&lt;purpose&gt;The 2005 Minnesota Legislature directed the Metropolitan Council to "carry out planning activities addressing the water supply needs of the metropolitan area" (Minnesota Statutes, Section 473.1565). Specifically the Council is charged with developing a base of technical information for water supply planning decisions and to prepare a metropolitan area master water supply plan. This dataset supports this charge.&lt;/purpose&gt;
			&lt;supplinf&gt;Twin Cities Metropolitan Area&lt;/supplinf&gt;
		&lt;/descript&gt;
		&lt;timeperd&gt;
			&lt;timeinfo&gt;
				&lt;sngdate&gt;
					&lt;caldate&gt;20090326&lt;/caldate&gt;
				&lt;/sngdate&gt;
			&lt;/timeinfo&gt;
			&lt;current&gt;Spring 2009&lt;/current&gt;
		&lt;/timeperd&gt;
		&lt;status&gt;
			&lt;progress&gt;Complete&lt;/progress&gt;
			&lt;update&gt;As Needed&lt;/update&gt;
		&lt;/status&gt;
		&lt;spdom&gt;
			&lt;bounding&gt;
				&lt;westbc&gt;-419964.72034215&lt;/westbc&gt;
				&lt;eastbc&gt;-521644.72034215&lt;/eastbc&gt;
				&lt;northbc&gt;5029183.7912165&lt;/northbc&gt;
				&lt;southbc&gt;4924223.7912165&lt;/southbc&gt;
			&lt;/bounding&gt;
		&lt;/spdom&gt;
		&lt;keywords&gt;
			&lt;place&gt;
				&lt;placekey&gt;Twin Cities, Minneapolis, St Paul&lt;/placekey&gt;
			&lt;/place&gt;
			&lt;theme&gt;
				&lt;themekey&gt;Recharge, Twin Cities, Groundwater, Model&lt;/themekey&gt;
				&lt;themekt&gt;None&lt;/themekt&gt;
			&lt;/theme&gt;
		&lt;/keywords&gt;
		&lt;accconst&gt;None&lt;/accconst&gt;
		&lt;useconst&gt;By acceptance of this data, the user agrees to include a copy of the metadata record, including the liability disclaimer, whenever the user transmits or provides the GIS data (or any portion of it) to another user.&lt;/useconst&gt;
		&lt;browse&gt;
			&lt;browsen&gt;None available&lt;/browsen&gt;
			&lt;browsed /&gt;
		&lt;/browse&gt;
		&lt;crossref&gt;
			&lt;citeinfo&gt;
				&lt;title&gt;Daily precipitation and maximum, minimum, and average daily air temperature collected by the US National Weather Service for the Downtown St. Paul Holman Field Airport station for the period January 1, 1975 - December 31, 2003.

GIS mapping of land cover from the United States Geological Survey (NLCD 2001)

Soil data from the Natural Resources Conservation Service Soil Survey Geographic Database (SSURGO)

Soil data from the Minnesota State Soil Atlas

1968 soil data in Wisconsin compiled by the Wisconsin Department of Natural Resources, the US Geological Survey, the Wisconsin Geological and Natural History Survey and the University of Wisconsin in 1987.

US Geological survey 30 meter square digital elevation models&lt;/title&gt;
			&lt;/citeinfo&gt;
		&lt;/crossref&gt;
		&lt;native&gt;Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 2; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.2.1.1332&lt;/native&gt;
		&lt;ptcontac&gt;
			&lt;cntinfo&gt;
				&lt;cntperp&gt;
					&lt;cntorg&gt;Metropolitan Council&lt;/cntorg&gt;
					&lt;cntper&gt;Lanya Ross&lt;/cntper&gt;
				&lt;/cntperp&gt;
				&lt;cntpos&gt;Sr. Environmental Scientist, Water Supply Planning&lt;/cntpos&gt;
				&lt;cntaddr&gt;
					&lt;address&gt;390 Robert Street North&lt;/address&gt;
					&lt;city&gt;St. Paul&lt;/city&gt;
					&lt;state&gt;MN&lt;/state&gt;
					&lt;postal&gt;55102&lt;/postal&gt;
				&lt;/cntaddr&gt;
				&lt;cntvoice&gt;651-602-1803&lt;/cntvoice&gt;
				&lt;cntfax&gt;651-602-1130&lt;/cntfax&gt;
				&lt;cntemail&gt;lanya.ross@metc.state.mn.us&lt;/cntemail&gt;
			&lt;/cntinfo&gt;
		&lt;/ptcontac&gt;
	&lt;/idinfo&gt;
	&lt;dataqual&gt;
		&lt;attracc&gt;
			&lt;attraccr&gt;The original concept behind the SWB code was to allow for the spatial distribution of groundwater recharge to be calculated based on readily available data and a standardized set of parameters (Dripps, 2003). Although the SWB code can certainly be applied using only available data and a &amp;#8220;standard&amp;#8221; set of curve numbers, it would be prudent to treat the results with caution as one should with any model output. In addition, there are underlying theoretical limitations that should be kept in mind when interpreting soil water balance model output. These limitations are discussed below.

The SWB model is designed for application to regional, rather than site-specific problems. Due to the regional scale of the input data and nature of the hydrologic models incorporated in it, the application of the SWB to site specific cases would provide at best an imprecise result lacking any true site specific characteristics. Much of this local imprecision is derived from the runoff curve method. The SWB model assumes that infiltration is the sum of precipitation, snowmelt, and inflow, minus the runoff calculated by means of the USDA-NRCS curve number method. The list of perceived flaws associated with the curve number method include (Garen and Moore, 2005):

1) the inability to identify runoff processes, source areas, or flow paths,
2) use of a watershed scale method that should not be applied at a plot or field scale, and
3) the method was developed to evaluate flood events and was not designed to simulate daily flows of ordinary magnitude.

In addition, it has been suggested that the curve number is not constant, but varies from event to event, and that the antecedent runoff condition only explains a portion of this variability (Hjelmfelt, 1991).

The recharge estimates produced by the SWB model are likely more reliable when averaged over time scales on the order of months to years. Although the code calculates recharge on a daily basis, there is no consideration of unsaturated zone flow. In locations where the depth to water table is substantial (more than several meters), there may be a significant lag between the time when SWB generates recharge, and the time when that recharge actually reaches the water table.

In areas with wetlands, springs, lakes, or other landscape features where the groundwater table is close to the land surface, the SWB code can be expected to perform poorly as there is currently no provision for recharge rejection via saturation excess, other than by specifying a maximum recharge rate for a particular land use and soil type combination. In most areas covered by the Metro Model, the depth to groundwater is deep enough to make this problem negligible.

The SWB model results are very sensitive to the soil hydrologic properties. The accuracy of the model results will depend heavily on the quality of the mapped soil properties used as input. For this project, the lack of uniform data over the relatively large domain modeled, required patching together data from several sources. The apparent lack of uniformity in soil mapping methodology between certain areas (see discussion above) probably introduces some error in the result. From this standpoint, the SWB model is probably most accurate when the soil data for the domain comes from a single reliable source.

Despite these limitations, the SWB model approach should be capable of generating reasonable mean annual or monthly groundwater recharge estimates at the scale of a small catchment. In order to do so, however, the SWB authors recommend up-scaling the daily results offered by the SWB model and averaging or filtering the results over a larger area (Dripps and Bradbury, 2007).&lt;/attraccr&gt;
		&lt;/attracc&gt;
		&lt;logic&gt;Unknown&lt;/logic&gt;
		&lt;complete&gt;Dataset is complete&lt;/complete&gt;
		&lt;posacc&gt;
			&lt;horizpa&gt;
				&lt;horizpar&gt;Unknown&lt;/horizpar&gt;
			&lt;/horizpa&gt;
			&lt;vertacc&gt;
				&lt;vertaccr&gt;Unknown&lt;/vertaccr&gt;
			&lt;/vertacc&gt;
		&lt;/posacc&gt;
		&lt;lineage&gt;
			&lt;procstep&gt;
				&lt;procdesc&gt;A soil-water balance (SWB) computer code was used to calculate spatial and temporal variations in groundwater recharge for the seven county Minneapolis - St. Paul metropolitan area in Minnesota. The input data used were obtained from readily available sources and integrated into the model using ARC/GIS tools. Calculated recharge rates generally compared well with calculations performed using other techniques.  

The code calculates components of the water balance on a daily basis, based on a modified version of the Thornthwaite-Mather soil-moisture balance approach (Thornthwaite, 1948; Thornthwaite and Mather, 1957). Data requirements include a number of commonly available tabular and gridded data types: 1) precipitation and temperature; 2) land use classification; 3) hydrologic soil group; 4) flow direction; and 5) soil water capacity. The data and formats required are designed to take advantage of widely available geographic information systems (GIS) datasets and file structures.

For input to the regional groundwater groundwater flow model, the average of all the individual annual outputs were used to create a 30m x 30m resolution grid of the "annual average recharge" for each grid cell. This grid was further translated using averages from a 30m x 30m grid to create a 500m x 500m grid to match the groundwater model resolution.

During the regional groundwater flow model cailbration process, the SWB-model calculated average annual recharge allowed to vary between a factor of 0.2344 and 1.6719. This range reflects the minimum and maximum average recharge values calculated for 1976-2003. The final regional groundwater flow model was calibrated using a recharge scaling factor of 0.7120579.

This dataset represents the final groundwater flow model-calibrated distribution of recharge across the Twin Cities metropolitan area, clipped to the extent of the seven-county area.&lt;/procdesc&gt;
			&lt;/procstep&gt;

		&lt;/lineage&gt;
	&lt;/dataqual&gt;

	&lt;spref&gt;
		&lt;vertdef&gt;
			&lt;altsys&gt;
				&lt;altdatum&gt;Not applicable&lt;/altdatum&gt;
			&lt;/altsys&gt;
		&lt;/vertdef&gt;
		&lt;horizsys&gt;
			&lt;planar&gt;
				&lt;gridsys&gt;
					&lt;gridsysn&gt;Universal Transverse Mercator&lt;/gridsysn&gt;
					&lt;utm&gt;
						&lt;utmzone&gt;15&lt;/utmzone&gt;
					&lt;/utm&gt;
				&lt;/gridsys&gt;
				&lt;planci&gt;
					&lt;plandu&gt;meters&lt;/plandu&gt;
					&lt;coordrep&gt;
						&lt;absres&gt;410.000000&lt;/absres&gt;
						&lt;ordres&gt;410.000000&lt;/ordres&gt;
					&lt;/coordrep&gt;
				&lt;/planci&gt;
			&lt;/planar&gt;
			&lt;geodetic&gt;
				&lt;horizdn&gt;NAD83&lt;/horizdn&gt;
				&lt;ellips&gt;GRS80&lt;/ellips&gt;
			&lt;/geodetic&gt;
		&lt;/horizsys&gt;
	&lt;/spref&gt;
	&lt;eainfo&gt;
		&lt;overview&gt;
			&lt;eadetcit&gt;None&lt;/eadetcit&gt;
		&lt;/overview&gt;
	&lt;/eainfo&gt;
	&lt;distinfo&gt;
		&lt;distliab&gt;NOTICE: The Geographic Information System (GIS) Data to which this notice is attached are made available pursuant to the Minnesota Government Data Practices Act (Minnesota Statutes Chapter 13). THE GIS DATA ARE PROVIDED TO YOU AS IS AND WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY AS TO THEIR PERFORMANCE, MERCHANTABILITY, OR FITNESS FOR ANY PARTICULAR PURPOSE. The GIS Data were developed by the Metropolitan Council for its own internal business purposes. The Metropolitan Council does not represent or warrant that the GIS Data or the data documentation are error-free, complete, current, or accurate. You are responsible for any consequences resulting from your use of the GIS Data or your reliance on the GIS Data. You should consult the data documentation for this particular GIS Data to determine the limitations of the GIS Data and the precision with which the GIS Data may depict distance, direction, location, or other geographic features. If you transmit or provide the GIS Data (or any portion of it) to another user, the GIS Data must include a copy of this disclaimer.&lt;/distliab&gt;
		&lt;stdorder&gt;
			&lt;digform&gt;
				&lt;digtinfo&gt;
					&lt;formname&gt;Arc Grid&lt;/formname&gt;
					&lt;formvern /&gt;
					&lt;transize /&gt;
				&lt;/digtinfo&gt;
			&lt;/digform&gt;
			&lt;ordering&gt;This dataset is distributed on the internet by clicking below after 'Online Linkage'. Doing so will tell your browser to download a 'ZIP' file which will contain the following: 

- ArcView shape files 
- metadata for the dataset (.htm) 
- NOTICE.RTF, an important notice about this dataset that can be read by any word processing software. 

This dataset can also be viewed and downloaded from the MetroGIS DataFinder Cafe at http://www.datafinder.org/cafe/ . The Cafe allows users to subset or clip datasets using an existing feature, such as a city or school district boundary or an ad-hoc, user defined area. 

Additionally, this dataset is available for direct use via one or more map services. More information about what a web mapping service is can be found at http://www.datafinder.org/services/ . The specific map service and layer name for this dataset can be found by clicking the blue or green boxes under the map service column of the DataFinder Catalog at http://www.datafinder.org/catalog/ .&lt;/ordering&gt;
		&lt;/stdorder&gt;
		&lt;distrib&gt;
			&lt;cntinfo&gt;
				&lt;cntpos&gt;Senior Enviromental Scientist&lt;/cntpos&gt;
				&lt;cntaddr&gt;
					&lt;address&gt;390 Robert Street North&lt;/address&gt;
					&lt;city&gt;St Paul&lt;/city&gt;
					&lt;state&gt;MN&lt;/state&gt;
					&lt;postal&gt;55101&lt;/postal&gt;
				&lt;/cntaddr&gt;
				&lt;cntvoice&gt;651-602-1803&lt;/cntvoice&gt;
				&lt;cntemail&gt;lanya.ross@metc.state.mn.us&lt;/cntemail&gt;
			&lt;/cntinfo&gt;
		&lt;/distrib&gt;
	&lt;/distinfo&gt;
	&lt;metainfo&gt;
		&lt;metd&gt;20090326&lt;/metd&gt;
		&lt;metstdn&gt;Minnesota Geographic Metadata Guidelines&lt;/metstdn&gt;
		&lt;metstdv&gt;1.2&lt;/metstdv&gt;
		&lt;metextns&gt;
			&lt;onlink&gt;http://www.gis.state.mn.us/stds/metadata.htm&lt;/onlink&gt;
		&lt;/metextns&gt;
		&lt;metc&gt;
			&lt;cntinfo&gt;
				&lt;cntperp&gt;
					&lt;cntper&gt;Evan Christianson&lt;/cntper&gt;
				&lt;/cntperp&gt;
				&lt;cntpos&gt;Sr. Environmental Scientist, Water Supply Planning&lt;/cntpos&gt;
				&lt;cntaddr&gt;
					&lt;address&gt;390 Robert Street North&lt;/address&gt;
					&lt;city&gt;St. Paul&lt;/city&gt;
					&lt;state&gt;MN&lt;/state&gt;
					&lt;postal&gt;55102&lt;/postal&gt;
				&lt;/cntaddr&gt;
				&lt;cntvoice&gt;651-602-1803&lt;/cntvoice&gt;
				&lt;cntfax&gt;651-602-1130&lt;/cntfax&gt;
				&lt;cntemail&gt;lanya.ross@metc.state.mn.us&lt;/cntemail&gt;
			&lt;/cntinfo&gt;
		&lt;/metc&gt;
	&lt;/metainfo&gt;

&lt;/metadata&gt;</field></doc></add>