<add allowDups="false"><doc><field name="LayerId">GeneralizedLandUseAcres1970to1997</field><field name="Name">GeneralizedLandUseAcres1970to1997</field><field name="CollectionId">initial collection</field><field name="Institution">Minnesota</field><field name="InstitutionSort">Minnesota</field><field name="Access">Public</field><field name="DataType" /><field name="DataTypeSort" /><field name="Availability">Online</field><field name="LayerDisplayName">Generalized Land Use Acreage Totals 1970 - 1997, Twin Cities Metropolitan Area</field><field name="LayerDisplayNameSort">Generalized Land Use Acreage Totals 1970 - 1997, Twin Cities Metropolitan Area</field><field name="Publisher">Metropolitan Council</field><field name="PublisherSort">Metropolitan Council</field><field name="Originator">Metropolitan Council</field><field name="OriginatorSort">Metropolitan Council</field><field name="ThemeKeywords">None</field><field name="PlaceKeywords">None</field><field name="Abstract">The Generalized Land Use Acreage Totals 1970 - 1997 database is a tabular data file.  It is NOT A GIS LAYER.  The table contains acreage totals by municipality for the years of 1970, 1975, 1980, 1984, 1990 &amp; 1997.  

The acreage totals are given by County-MCD.  County-MCD (field name ''COMCD'') is defined as the portion of a Minor Civil Division (municipality) that resides within a county.  Most, but not all MCDs reside entirely within one county. 

Totals are also provided for acres inside and outside the Metropolitan Urban Service Area (MUSA) for certain categories in 1990 and 1997.

The acreage totals for 1984, 1990 &amp; 1997 were derived from the Generalized Land Use - Historical GIS layer.  See the metadata for that layer for an explanation of the methodology and procedures used to create it.

In general, this dataset contains the categories of: single-family residential, multi-family residential, commercial, industrial, public/semi-public, airports, parks &amp; recreation, vacant/agricultural, highways, open water bodies, farm homesteads, industrial parks not developed, and public land not developed.  In 1997 the classes of Extractive and Public Industrial were added.

NOTES:
- Prior to 1984, very little information exists to document the methods used to calculate the land use acreage totals.
- The municipal boundaries information used for acreage calculations has changed over the years.  Some of this change reflects actual changes in corporate boundaries, other changes reflect new depictions of the same municipal boundaries.
- Categories used for summarizing land use acreage as well as the definitions of those categories have not remained completely consistent over time.
- Acreage totals are thought to get less accurate as they get older.
- Many problems have been found in the 1984 data and many more are likely to exist.
- The 1990 data uses a 2000 MUSA as defined in 1990 while the 1997 data MUSA definition is as of October of 1998.</field><field name="MaxY">45.415</field><field name="MinY">44.471</field><field name="MinX">-94.012</field><field name="MaxX">-92.732</field><field name="ContentDate">1997-04-14T00:00:00Z</field><field name="Location">{"download": "ftp://gisftp.metc.state.mn.us/GeneralizedLandUseAcres1970to1997.zip"}</field><field name="WorkspaceName" /><field name="FgdcText">&lt;?xml version="1.0"?&gt;&lt;metadata&gt;&lt;idinfo&gt;&lt;citation&gt;&lt;citeinfo&gt;&lt;origin&gt;Metropolitan Council&lt;/origin&gt;&lt;pubdate&gt;20000607&lt;/pubdate&gt;&lt;title&gt;Generalized Land Use Acreage Totals 1970 - 1997, Twin Cities Metropolitan Area&lt;/title&gt;&lt;mgmg1cid /&gt;&lt;pubinfo&gt;&lt;publish&gt;Metropolitan Council&lt;/publish&gt;&lt;/pubinfo&gt;&lt;onlink&gt;ftp://gisftp.metc.state.mn.us/GeneralizedLandUseAcres1970to1997.zip&lt;/onlink&gt;&lt;/citeinfo&gt;&lt;/citation&gt;&lt;descript&gt;&lt;abstract&gt;The Generalized Land Use Acreage Totals 1970 - 1997 database is a tabular data file.  It is NOT A GIS LAYER.  The table contains acreage totals by municipality for the years of 1970, 1975, 1980, 1984, 1990 &amp;amp; 1997.  

The acreage totals are given by County-MCD.  County-MCD (field name ''COMCD'') is defined as the portion of a Minor Civil Division (municipality) that resides within a county.  Most, but not all MCDs reside entirely within one county. 

Totals are also provided for acres inside and outside the Metropolitan Urban Service Area (MUSA) for certain categories in 1990 and 1997.

The acreage totals for 1984, 1990 &amp;amp; 1997 were derived from the Generalized Land Use - Historical GIS layer.  See the metadata for that layer for an explanation of the methodology and procedures used to create it.

In general, this dataset contains the categories of: single-family residential, multi-family residential, commercial, industrial, public/semi-public, airports, parks &amp;amp; recreation, vacant/agricultural, highways, open water bodies, farm homesteads, industrial parks not developed, and public land not developed.  In 1997 the classes of Extractive and Public Industrial were added.

NOTES:
- Prior to 1984, very little information exists to document the methods used to calculate the land use acreage totals.
- The municipal boundaries information used for acreage calculations has changed over the years.  Some of this change reflects actual changes in corporate boundaries, other changes reflect new depictions of the same municipal boundaries.
- Categories used for summarizing land use acreage as well as the definitions of those categories have not remained completely consistent over time.
- Acreage totals are thought to get less accurate as they get older.
- Many problems have been found in the 1984 data and many more are likely to exist.
- The 1990 data uses a 2000 MUSA as defined in 1990 while the 1997 data MUSA definition is as of October of 1998.&lt;/abstract&gt;&lt;purpose&gt;To aid in forecasting region-wide land supply and demand and to be used as a general regional planning tool.  This data does not indicate developability of land, but does include acres of 'Vacant and Agricultural' lands based on the definition described in Section 5 of this metadata.&lt;/purpose&gt;&lt;supplinf&gt;Twin Cities 7 County Metropolitan Area.  This includes the counties of Anoka, Carver, Dakota, Hennepin, Ramsey, Scott and Washington in Minnesota.&lt;/supplinf&gt;&lt;/descript&gt;&lt;timeperd&gt;&lt;timeinfo&gt;&lt;sngdate&gt;&lt;caldate&gt;19970414&lt;/caldate&gt;&lt;/sngdate&gt;&lt;/timeinfo&gt;&lt;current&gt;Air photos for the 1997 land use were taken Aprils 13th and 14th, 1997.  Photos for the 1990 land use were taken on May 4th &amp;amp; 5th, 1990.  Photos for the 1984 data were taken in spring of 1984.&lt;/current&gt;&lt;/timeperd&gt;&lt;status&gt;&lt;progress&gt;Complete&lt;/progress&gt;&lt;update&gt;Approximately every 5 years.&lt;/update&gt;&lt;/status&gt;&lt;spdom&gt;&lt;bounding&gt;&lt;westbc&gt;-94.012&lt;/westbc&gt;&lt;eastbc&gt;-92.732&lt;/eastbc&gt;&lt;northbc&gt;45.415&lt;/northbc&gt;&lt;southbc&gt;44.471&lt;/southbc&gt;&lt;/bounding&gt;&lt;/spdom&gt;&lt;keywords&gt;&lt;theme&gt;&lt;themekt&gt;None&lt;/themekt&gt;&lt;themekey&gt;Land Use, Land Type, planning and development&lt;/themekey&gt;&lt;/theme&gt;&lt;place&gt;&lt;placekey&gt;Twin Cities, Anoka County, Carver County, Dakota County, Hennepin County, Ramsey County, Scott County, Washington County&lt;/placekey&gt;&lt;/place&gt;&lt;/keywords&gt;&lt;accconst&gt;None&lt;/accconst&gt;&lt;useconst&gt;None&lt;/useconst&gt;&lt;browse&gt;&lt;browsen&gt;http://www.datafinder.org/metadata/SORRY_NO_SAMPLE_GRAPHIC_YET.htm&lt;/browsen&gt;&lt;browsed /&gt;&lt;/browse&gt;&lt;native&gt;Excel spreadsheet&lt;/native&gt;&lt;crossref&gt;&lt;citeinfo&gt;&lt;title&gt;Generalized Land Use - Historical 1984, 1990 &amp;amp; 1997&lt;/title&gt;&lt;/citeinfo&gt;&lt;/crossref&gt;&lt;ptcontac&gt;&lt;cntinfo&gt;&lt;cntperp&gt;&lt;cntorg&gt;Metropolitan Council&lt;/cntorg&gt;&lt;cntper&gt;Paul Hanson&lt;/cntper&gt;&lt;/cntperp&gt;&lt;cntpos&gt;GIS Coordinator&lt;/cntpos&gt;&lt;cntaddr&gt;&lt;addrtype&gt; mailing and physical address &lt;/addrtype&gt;&lt;address&gt;390 Robert Street North&lt;/address&gt;&lt;city&gt;St. Paul&lt;/city&gt;&lt;state&gt;Minnesota&lt;/state&gt;&lt;postal&gt;55101-1805&lt;/postal&gt;&lt;/cntaddr&gt;&lt;cntvoice&gt;651-602-1642&lt;/cntvoice&gt;&lt;cntfax&gt;651-602-1404&lt;/cntfax&gt;&lt;cntemail&gt;paul.hanson@metc.state.mn.us&lt;/cntemail&gt;&lt;/cntinfo&gt;&lt;/ptcontac&gt;&lt;/idinfo&gt;&lt;dataqual&gt;&lt;attracc&gt;&lt;attraccr&gt;For information about attribute accuracy for the years of 1984, 1990 and 1997, consult the metadata for the Generalized Land Use - Historical layer.

For other years, no information exist regarding attribute accuracy.&lt;/attraccr&gt;&lt;/attracc&gt;&lt;posacc&gt;&lt;horizpa&gt;&lt;horizpar&gt;Not Applicable&lt;/horizpar&gt;&lt;/horizpa&gt;&lt;/posacc&gt;&lt;lineage&gt;&lt;srcinfo&gt;&lt;srcscale /&gt;&lt;/srcinfo&gt;&lt;procstep&gt;&lt;procdesc&gt;For information about lineage for the years of 1984, 1990 and 1997, consult the metadata for the Generalized Land Use - Historical layer.

For other years, no information exist regarding lineage.

A note about MUSA calculations:  
Land use data is also provided for the Council's Metropolitan Urban Service Area (MUSA) for 1990 and 1997. The MUSA is an area defined by the Metropolitan Council where urban services are being planned to accommodate development up to a future point in time. For both the 1990 and 1997 land use data, a 2000 MUSA line is used. But this is not the same line because the MUSA line is adjusted over time to reflect more specific development proposals, as well as, development that has actually occurred. Areas may be added or subtracted from the MUSA, affecting both city level and regional MUSA figures. The 1990 data uses a 2000 MUSA as defined in 1990 while the 1997 data MUSA definition is as of October of 1998.&lt;/procdesc&gt;&lt;/procstep&gt;&lt;/lineage&gt;&lt;/dataqual&gt;&lt;spdoinfo&gt;&lt;indspref&gt;The unique identifier used for each row in the table is the COMCD field.  This field is a combination of the FIPS 3 digit county code and the FIPS 3 digit ''place'' code.  A COMCD is defined as the portion of a Minor Civil Division (municipality) that resides within a county. Most, but not all MCDs reside entirely within one county.&lt;/indspref&gt;&lt;direct /&gt;&lt;mgmg3obj /&gt;&lt;mgmg3til /&gt;&lt;/spdoinfo&gt;&lt;eainfo&gt;&lt;overview&gt;&lt;eaover&gt;The acreage totals in this dataset are given by County-MCD.  County-MCD (field 
name ''COMCD'') is defined as the portion of a Minor Civil Division
(municipality) that resides within a county.  Most, but not all MCDs reside 
entirely within one county.  Those that do not will be denoted as such in the 
COMCD_DESCRIP field. 
 
 
CO:         3 digit FIPS and state standard county code; e.g. 163, 003
 
CO_NAME:    County name; e.g. RAMSEY
 
MCD:        5 digit FIPS place code for minor civil divisions.
 
MCD_NAME:   MCD name; e.g. Burns Twp, Blaine.
 
COMCD_DESC: MCD description; e.g. Burns Township, 
                Blaine (Anoka Co. part)
 
COMCD:      8 digit code (combination of CO and MCD).
 
RES70:      1970 total residential acreage.
 
COMM70:     1970 total commercial acreage.
 
INDAIR70:   1970 total industrial acreage, including airports.
 
PUBREC70:   1970 total public and recreational acreage.
 
HWY70:      1970 total highway acreage.
 
NONURB70:   1970 total nonurbanized acreage (vacant/agricultural, industrial 
            vacant and public vacant acreage, and wetlands acreage in those 
            land uses).
 
WATER70:    1970 total water acreage.
 
RES75:      1975 total residential acreage.
 
COMM75:     1975 total commercial acreage.
 
INDAIR75:   1975 total industrial acreage, including airports.
 
PUBREC75:   1975 total public and recreational acreage.
 
HWY75:      1975 total highway acreage.
 
NONURB75:   1975 total nonurbanized acreage (vacant/agricultural, industrial 
            vacant and public vacant acreage, and wetlands acreage in those 
            categories.).
 
WATER75:    1975 total water acreage.
 
SF80:       1980 single-family residential acreage.
 
MF80:       1980 multifamily residential acreage.

IF80:       1980 isolated farm residential acreage.
 
COMM80:     1980 total commercial acreage.
 
INDAIR80:   1980 total industrial acreage, including airports. 
 
PUB80:      1980 total public acreage.
 
REC80:      1980 total recreational acreage.
 
HWY80:      1980 total highway acreage.
 
NONURB80:   1980 total nonurbanized acreage (vacant/agricultural, industrial 
            vacant and public vacant acreage, and wetlands acreage in those 
            categories).
 
WATER80:    1980 total water acreage.
 
SF84:       1984 single-family residential acreage.
 
MF84:       1984 multifamily residential acreage.
 
IF84:       1984 isolated farm residential acreage.
 
COMM84:     1984 total commercial acreage.
 
INDAIR84:   1984 total industrial acreage, including airports. 
 
PUB84:      1984 total public acreage.
 
REC84:      1984 total recreational acreage.
 
HWY84:      1984 total highway acreage.
 
NONURB84:   1984 total nonurbanized acreage (vacant/agricultural, industrial 
            vacant and public vacant acreage, and wetlands acreage in those 
            categories). 
 
WATER84:    1984 total water acreage.
 
SFMUSA90:   1990 single-family residential acreage in the MUSA.
 
MFMUSA90:   1990 multifamily residential acreage in the MUSA.
 
IFMUSA90:   1990 isolated farm residential acreage in the MUSA.
 
COMUSA90:   1990 total commercial acreage in the MUSA.
 
INDMUS90:   1990 industrial acreage in the MUSA
 
AIRMUS90:   1990 airport acreage in the MUSA. 
 
PUBMUS90:   1990 total public acreage in the MUSA.
 
RECMUS90:   1990 total recreational acreage in the MUSA.
 
HWYMUS90:   1990 total  highway acreage in the MUSA.
 
WETMUS90:   1990 wetlands acreage in the nonurbanized area
            (vacant/agricultural, industrial vacant and public vacant acreage) 
            in the MUSA.
 
AGMUSA90:   1990 total vacant and agricultural acreage in the MUSA, excluding 
            wetlands.
 
IVAMUS90:   1990 total industrial vacant acreage in the MUSA, excluding 
            wetlands.
 
PVAMUS90:   1990 total public vacant acreage in the MUSA, excluding wetlands.
 
WATMUS90:   1990 total water acreage in the MUSA.
 
SFTOT90:    1990 total single-family residential acreage.
 
MFTOT90:    1990 total multifamily residential acreage.
 
IFTOT90:    1990 total isolated farm residential acreage.
 
COMTOT90:   1990 total commercial acreage.
 
INDTOT90:   1990 industrial acreage.
 
AIRTOT90:   1990 airport acreage. 
 
PUBTOT90:   1990 total public acreage.
 
RECTOT90:   1990 total recreational acreage.
 
HWYTOT90:   1990 total highway acreage.
 
WETTOT90:   1990 wetlands acreage in the nonurbanized area 
            (vacant/agricultural, industrial vacant and public vacant acreage).
 
AGTOT90:    1990 total vacant and agricultural acreage, excluding wetlands.
 
IVATOT90:   1990 total industrial vacant acreage, excluding wetlands.
 
PVATOT90:   1990 total public vacant acreage, excluding wetlands.
 
WATTOT90:   1990 total water acreage.
 
SFMUSA97:   1997 single-family residential acreage in the MUSA.
 
MFMUSA97:   1997 multifamily residential acreage in the MUSA.
 
IFMUSA97:   1997 isolated farm residential acreage in the MUSA.
 
COMUSA97:   1997 total commercial acreage in the MUSA.
 
INDMUS97:   1997 industrial acreage in the MUSA, excluding public industrial 
            and extractive acreage.
 
PIMUSA97:   1997 public industrial acreage in the MUSA.
 
EXMUSA97:   1997 extractive acreage in the MUSA.
 
AIRMUS97:   1997 airport acreage in the MUSA. 
 
PUBMUS97:   1997 total public acreage in the MUSA.
 
RECMUS97:   1997 total recreational acreage in the MUSA.
 
HWYMUS97:   1997 total  highway acreage in the MUSA.
 
WETMUS97:   1997 wetlands acreage in the nonurbanized area 
            (vacant/agricultural, industrial vacant and public vacant acreage) 
            in the MUSA.
 
AGMUSA97:   1997 total vacant and agricultural acreage in the MUSA, excluding 
            wetlands.
 
IVAMUS97:   1997 total industrial vacant acreage in the MUSA, excluding 
            wetlands.
 
PVAMUS97:   1997 total public vacant acreage in the MUSA, excluding wetlands.
 
WATMUS97:   1997 total water acreage in the MUSA.
 
SFTOT97:    1997 total single-family residential acreage.
 
MFTOT97:    1997 total multifamily residential acreage.
 
IFTOT97:    1997 total isolated farm residential acreage.
 
COMTOT97:   1997 total commercial acreage.
 
INDTOT97:   1997 industrial acreage, excluding public industrial and extractive 
            acreage.
 
PITOT97:    1997 public industrial acreage
 
EXTOT97:    1997 extractive acreage.
 
AIRTOT97:   1997 airport acreage. 
 
PUBTOT97:   1997 total public acreage.
 
RECTOT97:   1997 total recreational acreage.
 
HWYTOT97:   1997 total highway acreage.
 
WETTOT97:   1997 wetlands acreage in the nonurbanized area 
            (vacant/agricultural, industrial vacant and public vacant acreage).
 
AGTOT97:    1997 total vacant and agricultural acreage, excluding wetlands.
 
IVATOT97:   1997 total industrial vacant acreage, excluding wetlands.
 
PVATOT97:   1997 total public vacant acreage, excluding wetlands.
 
WATTOT97:   1997 total water acreage.&lt;/eaover&gt;&lt;eadetcit&gt;The original categories used for land use breakdowns were established in 1962 and have been modified slightly over the years.  The classes for the 1997 land use layer are as follows:

1 - Single Family Residential
Includes all individual, free standing single family housing (including manufactured housing).  Within the MUSA (metropolitan urban service area) and in residential developments outside the MUSA, the lot lines visible on the photos were used for determining residential land use boundaries.  Where residential developments were visibly not complete, the undeveloped area was classified as vacant.  For the scattered, rural residential areas outside the MUSA, only the portion of lots used for residences was assigned to the residential category.

2 - Multi-Family Residential
Includes all multiple dwelling units such as duplexes, bungalows, twin homes, townhouses, quad homes and apartment complexes.  Also, buildings that are primarily apartments that have some group dining facilities are included (however, not those buildings that fit the census definition of 'Group Quarters', such as, dormitories, nursing homes or medical care facilities).

3 - Commercial
Includes all retail sales, services, hotels and motels, health care facilities (e.g. medical and dental clinics and offices and medical laboratories, but not hospitals and nursing homes) and recreational services that are predominantly privately owned and operated for profit (e.g. theaters, bowling alleys, equestrian ranches) except golf courses.  Hospitals and nursing homes are included in the 'Public &amp;amp; Semi-Public' category and golf courses are in the 'Parks &amp;amp; Recreation Areas' class.  For large shopping centers, only actual developed areas are shown.  This is done so that over the years new development can be shown (e.g. restaurants or gas stations on perimeter roads).

4 - Industrial
Includes the Federal Standard Industrial Classification (SIC) codes 14 through 50.  This includes manufacturing, transportation, construction, communications, utilities, and wholesale trade.  Also included in the 'Industrial' category are some horticultural specialty land uses (e.g. large greenhouses that do not sell to the public).  As of 1997, gravel pits and quarrying have been placed in a new category called 'Extractive' and all publicly owned areas that are predominantly of industrial nature have been placed in a new category called 'Public Industrial.'

5 - Public Semi-Public
Includes the land under and adjacent to schools (public and private), hospitals, churches, cemeteries, ice arenas and all facilities of local, state and federal governments, including convalescent homes, mental institutions and penal facilities maintained by any level of government.  All lands within the boundaries of these institutions and facilities are included in this category.  However, in certain instances unused lands were included in the 'Public &amp;amp; Semi-Public Vacant' category (e.g. the University of Minnesota's property in Rosemount, or part of the land adjacent to the Minnesota Veterans Home in Hastings).

6 - Airports
All types of airports.

7 - Parks &amp;amp; Recreation Areas
Includes all parks (city, regional and state), wildlife refuges, playgrounds, zoos, gun clubs, golf courses and similar areas (this includes DNR wildlife management areas and scientific and natural areas).  Parks are delineated using their actual boundaries taken directly off comprehensive plans, park maps or county parcel data.

8 - Vacant/Agricultural
Includes land identifiable from aerial photos as open and in agriculture uses, other uses where no buildings are present or unused land.  Please note that indoor horticultural specialty land uses (the growing of nursery stock, flowers, seeds, sod and food crops in large greenhouses that do not sell to the public; and large concentrations of agricultural buildings (e.g., barns, sheds and silos)) are included in the 'Industrial' category where they can be delineated.  Where residential uses are on larger lots, the residential land use category my include only the house and mowed portion of the parcel, with the rest being placed in this Vacant and Agricultural category.

9 - Major Four Lane Highways
Includes only the major interstate freeways and 4 lane divided highways with rights-of-way of 200 feet or greater.  Also included in 1997 are all 4-lane roads with a Metropolitan Council functional class designation of 'Principal Arterial.'

10 - Open Water Bodies
Includes lakes larger than 5 acres and rivers wider than 200 feet.

11 - Farmsteads
Includes only that portion of land that encompasses the buildings on the farmstead.

12 - Extractive
New category in 1997.  Includes all gravel pits and quarries.

41 - Industrial Parks not Developed
Parcels of land in a designated (named) industrial park but not developed.

51 - Public &amp;amp; Semi-Public Vacant
A government or university owned parcel of land that is undeveloped (e.g. part of arsenal site in Arden Hills or the University property in Rosemount).

54 - Public Industrial
New category in 1997.  Includes all publicly owned areas that are predominantly of an industrial nature (e.g. waste water treatment plants, city bus garages, and Dept. of Transportation sand and salt stockpiling areas).  In the past, some of these have been coded as industrial and others as public.&lt;/eadetcit&gt;&lt;/overview&gt;&lt;/eainfo&gt;&lt;distinfo&gt;&lt;resdesc&gt;GeneralizedLandUseAcres1970to1997&lt;/resdesc&gt;&lt;distliab&gt;NOTICE:  The Geographic Information System (GIS) Data to which this notice is attached are made available pursuant to the Minnesota Government Data Practices Act (Minnesota Statutes Chapter 13).  THE GIS DATA ARE PROVIDED TO YOU AS IS AND WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY AS TO THEIR PERFORMANCE, MERCHANTABILITY, OR FITNESS FOR ANY PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  The GIS Data were developed by the Metropolitan Council for its own internal business purposes.  The Metropolitan Council does not represent or warrant that the GIS Data or the data documentation are error-free, complete, current, or accurate.  You are responsible for any consequences resulting from your use of the GIS Data or your reliance on the GIS Data.  You should consult the data documentation for this particular GIS Data to determine the limitations of the GIS Data and the precision with which the GIS Data may depict distance, direction, location, or other geographic features.  If you transmit or provide the GIS Data (or any portion of it) to another user, it is recommended that the GIS Data include a copy of this disclaimer and this metadata.&lt;/distliab&gt;&lt;stdorder&gt;&lt;digform&gt;&lt;digtinfo&gt;&lt;formname&gt;dBase file and Excel file&lt;/formname&gt;&lt;formvern /&gt;&lt;transize&gt;Less than 1 Mb for zip file.&lt;/transize&gt;&lt;/digtinfo&gt;&lt;/digform&gt;&lt;ordering&gt;This dataset is distributed on the internet by clicking below after 'Online Linkage'.  Doing so will tell your browser to download a 'ZIP' file which will contain the following:

- dBase file
- Excel file
- metadata for the dataset (.htm)
- NOTICE.RTF, an important notice about this dataset that can be read by any word processing software.&lt;/ordering&gt;&lt;/stdorder&gt;&lt;distrib&gt;&lt;cntinfo&gt;&lt;cntperp&gt;&lt;cntorg&gt;Metropolitan Council&lt;/cntorg&gt;&lt;cntper&gt;Jon Hoekenga&lt;/cntper&gt;&lt;/cntperp&gt;&lt;cntpos&gt;GIS System Administrator&lt;/cntpos&gt;&lt;cntaddr&gt;&lt;address&gt;390 Robert Street North&lt;/address&gt;&lt;city&gt;St. Paul&lt;/city&gt;&lt;state&gt;MN&lt;/state&gt;&lt;postal&gt;55101-1805&lt;/postal&gt;&lt;/cntaddr&gt;&lt;cntvoice&gt;651.602.1561&lt;/cntvoice&gt;&lt;cntemail&gt;jonathan.hoekenga@metc.state.mn.us&lt;/cntemail&gt;&lt;/cntinfo&gt;&lt;/distrib&gt;&lt;/distinfo&gt;&lt;metainfo&gt;&lt;metd&gt;20001128&lt;/metd&gt;&lt;metstdn&gt;Minnesota Geographic Metadata Guidelines&lt;/metstdn&gt;&lt;metstdv&gt;1.2&lt;/metstdv&gt;&lt;metextns&gt;&lt;onlink&gt;http://www.gis.state.mn.us/stds/metadata.htm&lt;/onlink&gt;&lt;/metextns&gt;&lt;metc&gt;&lt;cntinfo&gt;&lt;cntperp&gt;&lt;cntorg&gt;Metropolitan Council&lt;/cntorg&gt;&lt;cntper&gt;Jon Hoekenga&lt;/cntper&gt;&lt;/cntperp&gt;&lt;cntpos&gt;GIS System Administrator&lt;/cntpos&gt;&lt;cntaddr&gt;&lt;address&gt;390 Robert Street North&lt;/address&gt;&lt;city&gt;St. Paul&lt;/city&gt;&lt;state&gt;MN&lt;/state&gt;&lt;postal&gt;55101-1805&lt;/postal&gt;&lt;/cntaddr&gt;&lt;cntvoice&gt;651.602.1561&lt;/cntvoice&gt;&lt;cntemail&gt;jonathan.hoekenga@metc.state.mn.us&lt;/cntemail&gt;&lt;/cntinfo&gt;&lt;/metc&gt;&lt;/metainfo&gt;&lt;Esri&gt;&lt;ModDate&gt;20110729&lt;/ModDate&gt;&lt;ModTime&gt;13573400&lt;/ModTime&gt;&lt;/Esri&gt;&lt;mdDateSt Sync="TRUE"&gt;20110729&lt;/mdDateSt&gt;&lt;/metadata&gt;</field></doc></add>