<add allowDups="false"><doc><field name="LayerId">LakesAndRivers</field><field name="Name">0</field><field name="CollectionId">initial collection</field><field name="Institution">Minnesota</field><field name="InstitutionSort">Minnesota</field><field name="Access">Public</field><field name="DataType">Polygon</field><field name="DataTypeSort">Polygon</field><field name="Availability">Online</field><field name="LayerDisplayName">Lakes and Rivers - Open Water Features</field><field name="LayerDisplayNameSort">Lakes and Rivers - Open Water Features</field><field name="Publisher">Metropolitan Council</field><field name="PublisherSort">Metropolitan Council</field><field name="Originator">Metropolitan Council</field><field name="OriginatorSort">Metropolitan Council</field><field name="ThemeKeywords">None</field><field name="PlaceKeywords">None</field><field name="Abstract">This layer depicts open water features for lakes and rivers. The geography was initially created from the open water features depicted in the 2005 Generalized Land Use dataset developed by the Metropolitan Council. It is being updated over time with data from a variety of sources. It includes lakes larger than 3 acres and rivers wider than 200 feet. It may also include some smaller open water features as needed by the Metropolitan Council, including all lakes in the Council's lake monitoirng program. This layer does not depict the satutory Ordinary High Water Level of lakes. 

NOTES: 
- This dataset is derived from the Master Open Water Features dataset published by the Met Council.
- The extent of water features varies seasonally and annually with rainfall. The extent of water shown in this dataset may not reflect the current status of a particular water feature.
- When adding new polygons or modifying existing polygons, we will create boundaries based on recent imagery that we think depicts average water levels. We will NOT try to adjust the boundaries for seasonal variations in water levels.   
- Wastewater stabilization ponds, which can be quite large, are not shown in this layer. </field><field name="MaxY">45.418</field><field name="MinY">44.457</field><field name="MinX">-94.026</field><field name="MaxX">-92.715</field><field name="ContentDate">2010-04-01T00:00:00Z</field><field name="Location">{"download": "ftp://gisftp.metc.state.mn.us/LakesAndRivers.zip", "ArcGISRest": "http://gis2.metc.state.mn.us/ArcGIS/rest/services/MetroGIS/Water_Resources/MapServer/export"}</field><field name="WorkspaceName" /><field name="FgdcText">&lt;?xml version="1.0"?&gt;&lt;metadata&gt;&lt;idinfo&gt;&lt;citation&gt;&lt;citeinfo&gt;&lt;title&gt;Lakes and Rivers - Open Water Features&lt;/title&gt;&lt;origin&gt;Metropolitan Council&lt;/origin&gt;&lt;pubinfo&gt;&lt;publish&gt;Metropolitan Council&lt;/publish&gt;&lt;/pubinfo&gt;&lt;pubdate&gt;Periodically revised&lt;/pubdate&gt;&lt;onlink&gt;ftp://gisftp.metc.state.mn.us/LakesAndRivers.zip&lt;/onlink&gt;&lt;/citeinfo&gt;&lt;/citation&gt;&lt;descript&gt;&lt;abstract&gt;This layer depicts open water features for lakes and rivers. The geography was initially created from the open water features depicted in the 2005 Generalized Land Use dataset developed by the Metropolitan Council. It is being updated over time with data from a variety of sources. It includes lakes larger than 3 acres and rivers wider than 200 feet. It may also include some smaller open water features as needed by the Metropolitan Council, including all lakes in the Council's lake monitoirng program. This layer does not depict the satutory Ordinary High Water Level of lakes. 

NOTES: 
- This dataset is derived from the Master Open Water Features dataset published by the Met Council.
- The extent of water features varies seasonally and annually with rainfall. The extent of water shown in this dataset may not reflect the current status of a particular water feature.
- When adding new polygons or modifying existing polygons, we will create boundaries based on recent imagery that we think depicts average water levels. We will NOT try to adjust the boundaries for seasonal variations in water levels.   
- Wastewater stabilization ponds, which can be quite large, are not shown in this layer. &lt;/abstract&gt;&lt;purpose&gt;A general depiction of lakes and rivers in the metro area that is periodically updated.&lt;/purpose&gt;&lt;supplinf&gt;Generally the Twin Cities 7 County Metropolitan Area. This includes the counties of Anoka, Carver, Dakota, Hennepin, Ramsey, Scott and Washington in Minnesota. The boundaries of lakes that cross the outer boundary of the 7 county Metropolitan Area are completed. Lakes outside of the 7 county metropolitan area that have been part of the Council's lake monitoring program are also included.&lt;/supplinf&gt;&lt;/descript&gt;&lt;timeperd&gt;&lt;timeinfo&gt;&lt;sngdate&gt;&lt;caldate&gt;20100401&lt;/caldate&gt;&lt;/sngdate&gt;&lt;/timeinfo&gt;&lt;current&gt;The time period data indicates the last time when any significant update of the dataset has occured. The original data were derived from the Met Council's generalized land use data which used ground condition (air photos) as of May 13th and 14th, 2005. The data have since been updated on a periodic basis. The dataset was substantially updated using air photos from mid-April 2010.&lt;/current&gt;&lt;/timeperd&gt;&lt;status&gt;&lt;progress&gt;Complete&lt;/progress&gt;&lt;update&gt;As Needed&lt;/update&gt;&lt;/status&gt;&lt;spdom&gt;&lt;bounding&gt;&lt;westbc&gt;-94.026&lt;/westbc&gt;&lt;eastbc&gt;-92.715&lt;/eastbc&gt;&lt;northbc&gt;45.418&lt;/northbc&gt;&lt;southbc&gt;44.457&lt;/southbc&gt;&lt;/bounding&gt;&lt;/spdom&gt;&lt;keywords&gt;&lt;place&gt;&lt;placekey&gt;Twin Cities, Anoka County, Carver County, Dakota County, Hennepin County, Ramsey County, Scott County, Washington County&lt;/placekey&gt;&lt;/place&gt;&lt;theme&gt;&lt;themekey&gt;Lakes, rivers, open water features, water features, water&lt;/themekey&gt;&lt;themekt&gt;None&lt;/themekt&gt;&lt;/theme&gt;&lt;/keywords&gt;&lt;accconst&gt;None&lt;/accconst&gt;&lt;useconst&gt;None&lt;/useconst&gt;&lt;browse&gt;&lt;browsed&gt;Sample map showing the lakes and rivers layer.&lt;/browsed&gt;&lt;/browse&gt;&lt;crossref&gt;&lt;citeinfo&gt;&lt;title&gt;Master Open Water Features&lt;/title&gt;&lt;/citeinfo&gt;&lt;/crossref&gt;&lt;native&gt;ArcGIS Version 9x&lt;/native&gt;&lt;ptcontac&gt;&lt;cntinfo&gt;&lt;cntperp&gt;&lt;cntorg&gt;Metropolitan Council&lt;/cntorg&gt;&lt;cntper&gt;Emily Resseger&lt;/cntper&gt;&lt;/cntperp&gt;&lt;cntpos&gt;Principal Environmental Scientist&lt;/cntpos&gt;&lt;cntaddr&gt;&lt;address&gt;390 Robert Street North&lt;/address&gt;&lt;city&gt;St. Paul&lt;/city&gt;&lt;state&gt;MN&lt;/state&gt;&lt;postal&gt;55101-1805&lt;/postal&gt;&lt;/cntaddr&gt;&lt;cntvoice&gt;651.602.1033&lt;/cntvoice&gt;&lt;cntemail&gt;emily.resseger@metc.state.mn.us&lt;/cntemail&gt;&lt;/cntinfo&gt;&lt;/ptcontac&gt;&lt;/idinfo&gt;&lt;dataqual&gt;&lt;attracc&gt;&lt;attraccr&gt;Lake ID and names were assigned by spatially joining a point dataset obtained from the DNR Division of Waters. The accuracy of the attributes in the source dataset is not known. The accuracy of the spatial join was visually inspected and verified to ensure accurate assignment of these data.&lt;/attraccr&gt;&lt;/attracc&gt;&lt;complete&gt;Entire seven county metro area is covered.&lt;/complete&gt;&lt;posacc&gt;&lt;horizpa&gt;&lt;horizpar&gt;For original data, boundaries of open water features were based on the 0.6 meter resolution digital orthophotos taken in May 2005. The scale at which lines were digitized varied as staff zoomed in and out while heads-up digitizing within ArcView, however most lines were digitized at an on-screen scale of no higher than 1:3000. In highly urbanized areas, 1:1500 was more common. 

Subsequent updates have come from a variety of sources, including the East-Central MN one foot orthophotos flown in April 2010, and the 1-meter FSA NAIP imagery flown in summer of 2010.

As a general rule when developing this dataset it was the Metropolitan Council's intention to meet or exceed the National Mapping Accuracy Standards at 1:24,000 (within approximately 40 feet of actual location). No testing has been conducted to verify this.&lt;/horizpar&gt;&lt;/horizpa&gt;&lt;/posacc&gt;&lt;lineage&gt;&lt;procstep&gt;&lt;procdesc&gt;These water features were extracted from the Metropolitan Council's 2005 landuse dataset. Water feature boundaries were heads-up digitized from 0.6 meter digital orthophotos. The scale at which lines were digitized varied as staff zoomed in and out while heads-up digitizing within ArcView, however most lines were digitized at an on-screen scale of no higher than 1:3000. In highly urbanized areas, 1:1500 was more common. 

Land use data development procedures called for digitizing lakes larger than 3 acres and rivers wider than 200 feet. The dataset may also include some smaller open water features. 

DATA SOURCES: 
- 2005 MARKHURD Digital Orthophoto quarter quads (0.6 meter resolution) 
- 2000 land use delineations 

Lake ID and names were assigned by spatially joining a point dataset obtained from the DNR Division of Waters. The accuracy of the spatial join was visually inspected and verified to ensure accurate assignment of these data.&lt;/procdesc&gt;&lt;/procstep&gt;&lt;srcinfo&gt;&lt;srcscale /&gt;&lt;/srcinfo&gt;&lt;/lineage&gt;&lt;/dataqual&gt;&lt;spdoinfo&gt;&lt;indspref&gt;DNR Lake ID&lt;/indspref&gt;&lt;direct&gt;Vector&lt;/direct&gt;&lt;mgmg3obj&gt;polygon shapes&lt;/mgmg3obj&gt;&lt;mgmg3til&gt;One layer for entire metro area&lt;/mgmg3til&gt;&lt;/spdoinfo&gt;&lt;eainfo&gt;&lt;detailed&gt;&lt;enttyp&gt;&lt;enttypl&gt;new_entity&lt;/enttypl&gt;&lt;/enttyp&gt;&lt;/detailed&gt;&lt;overview&gt;&lt;eaover&gt;OWF_ID: A unique 8 character identifier for each open water feature polygon. The value of this field is the Minnesota DNR DOWLKNUM ID if one has been assigned by the DNR. Where no DOWLKNUM has been assigned, a unique sequential number assigned by the Met Council is used, all starting with "99...". For the rivers in the dataset, the GNIS ID for the river is used. 

SYSTEM: Differentiates lacustrine open water features (Lakes) from riverine open water features (Rivers). 

NAME_DNR: The DNR registered name of the lake, if one exists. 

ALT_NAME: The alternative name of the lake.  The source of this is usually the DNR&amp;#8217;s Protected Waters dataset or the Metropolitan Council&amp;#8217;s Lake Annotation Classes.

AREA_ACRES: The area of the polygon feature in acres.&lt;/eaover&gt;&lt;/overview&gt;&lt;/eainfo&gt;&lt;distinfo&gt;&lt;resdesc&gt;LakesAndRivers&lt;/resdesc&gt;&lt;distliab&gt;NOTICE:  The Geographic Information System (GIS) Data to which this notice is attached are made available pursuant to the Minnesota Government Data Practices Act (Minnesota Statutes Chapter 13).  THE GIS DATA ARE PROVIDED TO YOU AS IS AND WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY AS TO THEIR PERFORMANCE, MERCHANTABILITY, OR FITNESS FOR ANY PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  The GIS Data were developed by the Metropolitan Council for its own internal business purposes.  The Metropolitan Council does not represent or warrant that the GIS Data or the data documentation are error-free, complete, current, or accurate.  You are responsible for any consequences resulting from your use of the GIS Data or your reliance on the GIS Data.  You should consult the data documentation for this particular GIS Data to determine the limitations of the GIS Data and the precision with which the GIS Data may depict distance, direction, location, or other geographic features.  If you transmit or provide the GIS Data (or any portion of it) to another user, it is recommended that the GIS Data include a copy of this disclaimer and this metadata.&lt;/distliab&gt;&lt;stdorder&gt;&lt;digform&gt;&lt;digtinfo&gt;&lt;formname&gt;ArcView Shape File&lt;/formname&gt;&lt;formvern&gt;ArcGIS 9x&lt;/formvern&gt;&lt;transize&gt;Approximately 3 Mb for zip file.&lt;/transize&gt;&lt;/digtinfo&gt;&lt;/digform&gt;&lt;ordering&gt;This dataset is distributed on the internet by clicking below after 'Online Linkage'.  Doing so will tell your browser to download a 'ZIP' file which will contain the following:

- ArcView shape files
- metadata for the dataset (.htm)
- NOTICE.RTF, an important notice about this dataset that can be read by any word processing software.

Additionally, this dataset is available for direct use via one or more map services.  More information about what a map service is can be found at http://www.datafinder.org/services/.  The specific map service and layer name for this dataset can be found by clicking the "Services" link for this dataset in the DataFinder Catalog at http://www.datafinder.org/catalog/ .&lt;/ordering&gt;&lt;/stdorder&gt;&lt;distrib&gt;&lt;cntinfo&gt;&lt;cntperp&gt;&lt;cntorg&gt;Metropolitan Council&lt;/cntorg&gt;&lt;cntper&gt;Jon Hoekenga&lt;/cntper&gt;&lt;/cntperp&gt;&lt;cntpos&gt;GIS Specialist&lt;/cntpos&gt;&lt;cntaddr&gt;&lt;address&gt;390 Robert Street North&lt;/address&gt;&lt;city&gt;St. Paul&lt;/city&gt;&lt;state&gt;MN&lt;/state&gt;&lt;postal&gt;55101-1805&lt;/postal&gt;&lt;/cntaddr&gt;&lt;cntvoice&gt;651.602.1561&lt;/cntvoice&gt;&lt;cntemail&gt;jonathan.hoekenga@metc.state.mn.us&lt;/cntemail&gt;&lt;/cntinfo&gt;&lt;/distrib&gt;&lt;/distinfo&gt;&lt;metainfo&gt;&lt;metd&gt;20130520&lt;/metd&gt;&lt;metstdn&gt;Minnesota Geographic Metadata Guidelines&lt;/metstdn&gt;&lt;metstdv&gt;1.2&lt;/metstdv&gt;&lt;metextns&gt;&lt;onlink&gt;http://www.gis.state.mn.us/stds/metadata.htm&lt;/onlink&gt;&lt;/metextns&gt;&lt;metc&gt;&lt;cntinfo&gt;&lt;cntperp&gt;&lt;cntorg&gt;Metropolitan Council&lt;/cntorg&gt;&lt;cntper&gt;Jon Hoekenga&lt;/cntper&gt;&lt;/cntperp&gt;&lt;cntpos&gt;GIS Specialist&lt;/cntpos&gt;&lt;cntaddr&gt;&lt;address&gt;390 Robert Street North&lt;/address&gt;&lt;city&gt;St. Paul&lt;/city&gt;&lt;state&gt;MN&lt;/state&gt;&lt;postal&gt;55101-1805&lt;/postal&gt;&lt;/cntaddr&gt;&lt;cntvoice&gt;651.602.1561&lt;/cntvoice&gt;&lt;cntemail&gt;jonathan.hoekenga@metc.state.mn.us&lt;/cntemail&gt;&lt;/cntinfo&gt;&lt;/metc&gt;&lt;/metainfo&gt;&lt;Esri&gt;&lt;ModDate&gt;20110729&lt;/ModDate&gt;&lt;ModTime&gt;14270400&lt;/ModTime&gt;&lt;/Esri&gt;&lt;mdDateSt Sync="TRUE"&gt;20110729&lt;/mdDateSt&gt;&lt;spref&gt;&lt;horizsys&gt;&lt;planar&gt;&lt;gridsys&gt;&lt;gridsysn&gt;Universal Transverse Mercator&lt;/gridsysn&gt;&lt;utm&gt;&lt;utmzone&gt;15&lt;/utmzone&gt;&lt;/utm&gt;&lt;/gridsys&gt;&lt;planci&gt;&lt;plandu&gt;meters&lt;/plandu&gt;&lt;/planci&gt;&lt;/planar&gt;&lt;geodetic&gt;&lt;horizdn&gt;NAD83&lt;/horizdn&gt;&lt;ellips&gt;GRS80&lt;/ellips&gt;&lt;/geodetic&gt;&lt;/horizsys&gt;&lt;/spref&gt;&lt;/metadata&gt;</field></doc></add>