<add allowDups="false"><doc><field name="LayerId">NRIAStreamsNetworkTable</field><field name="Name">NRIAStreamsNetworkTable</field><field name="CollectionId">initial collection</field><field name="Institution">Minnesota</field><field name="InstitutionSort">Minnesota</field><field name="Access">Public</field><field name="DataType" /><field name="DataTypeSort" /><field name="Availability">Online</field><field name="LayerDisplayName">Natural Resource Inventory Table for Streams</field><field name="LayerDisplayNameSort">Natural Resource Inventory Table for Streams</field><field name="Publisher">Metropolitan Council</field><field name="PublisherSort">Metropolitan Council</field><field name="Originator">Metropolitan Council</field><field name="OriginatorSort">Metropolitan Council</field><field name="ThemeKeywords">None</field><field name="PlaceKeywords">None</field><field name="Abstract">This dataset is a table of characteristics related to the ecological, recreational, and water supply uses of streams in the Twin Cities Metropolitan Area. Data on these characteristics are drawn from a variety of sources including the DNR and Met Council. This table also includes several calculated fields. Additional information about the source of these data is given in the Entity and Attribute section of this metadata. These tables can be linked to a geographic representation of streams through the Stream_net_dslv data layer.

These data were created as a part of a natural resource inventory and assessment for the Twin Cities Metropolitan Area.</field><field name="MaxY">45.415</field><field name="MinY">44.471</field><field name="MinX">-94.012</field><field name="MaxX">-92.732</field><field name="ContentDate">2002-01-01T00:00:00Z</field><field name="Location">{"download": "ftp://gisftp.metc.state.mn.us/NRIAStreamsNetworkTable.zip"}</field><field name="WorkspaceName" /><field name="FgdcText">&lt;?xml version="1.0"?&gt;&lt;metadata&gt;
	&lt;idinfo&gt;
		&lt;citation&gt;
			&lt;citeinfo&gt;
				&lt;origin&gt;Metropolitan Council&lt;/origin&gt;
				&lt;pubdate&gt;20030402&lt;/pubdate&gt;
				&lt;title&gt;Natural Resource Inventory Table for Streams&lt;/title&gt;
				&lt;mgmg1cid&gt;N/A&lt;/mgmg1cid&gt;
				&lt;pubinfo&gt;
					&lt;publish&gt;Metropolitan Council&lt;/publish&gt;
				&lt;/pubinfo&gt;
				&lt;onlink&gt;ftp://gisftp.metc.state.mn.us/NRIAStreamsNetworkTable.zip&lt;/onlink&gt;
			&lt;/citeinfo&gt;
		&lt;/citation&gt;
		&lt;descript&gt;
			&lt;abstract&gt;This dataset is a table of characteristics related to the ecological, recreational, and water supply uses of streams in the Twin Cities Metropolitan Area. Data on these characteristics are drawn from a variety of sources including the DNR and Met Council. This table also includes several calculated fields. Additional information about the source of these data is given in the Entity and Attribute section of this metadata. These tables can be linked to a geographic representation of streams through the Stream_net_dslv data layer.

These data were created as a part of a natural resource inventory and assessment for the Twin Cities Metropolitan Area.&lt;/abstract&gt;
			&lt;purpose&gt;This dataset was developed as a resource for incorporating natural resource protection in to plans for accomodating future growth and development in the Twin Cities. The data are intended to provide a relative rank of the potential regional significance of streams for ecological, recreational, and water supply uses.&lt;/purpose&gt;
			&lt;supplinf&gt;Twin Cities 7 County Metropolitan Area.  This includes the counties of Anoka, Carver, Dakota, Hennepin, Ramsey, Scott and Washington in Minnesota.&lt;/supplinf&gt;
		&lt;/descript&gt;
		&lt;timeperd&gt;
			&lt;timeinfo&gt;
				&lt;sngdate&gt;
					&lt;caldate&gt;2002&lt;/caldate&gt;
				&lt;/sngdate&gt;
			&lt;/timeinfo&gt;
			&lt;current&gt;2002 Natural Resource Inventory and Assessment&lt;/current&gt;
		&lt;/timeperd&gt;
		&lt;status&gt;
			&lt;progress&gt;Complete&lt;/progress&gt;
			&lt;update&gt;None planned&lt;/update&gt;
		&lt;/status&gt;
		&lt;spdom&gt;
			&lt;bounding&gt;
				&lt;westbc&gt;-94.012&lt;/westbc&gt;
				&lt;eastbc&gt;-92.732&lt;/eastbc&gt;
				&lt;northbc&gt;45.415&lt;/northbc&gt;
				&lt;southbc&gt;44.471&lt;/southbc&gt;
			&lt;/bounding&gt;
		&lt;/spdom&gt;
		&lt;keywords&gt;
			&lt;theme&gt;
				&lt;themekt&gt;None&lt;/themekt&gt;
				&lt;themekey&gt;natural resource, inventory, assessment, water, streams, rivers, water resources&lt;/themekey&gt;
			&lt;/theme&gt;
			&lt;place&gt;
				&lt;placekey&gt;Twin Cities, Anoka County, Carver County, Dakota County, Hennepin County, Ramsey County, Scott County, Washington County&lt;/placekey&gt;
			&lt;/place&gt;
		&lt;/keywords&gt;
		&lt;accconst&gt;None&lt;/accconst&gt;
		&lt;useconst&gt;None&lt;/useconst&gt;
		&lt;ptcontac&gt;
			&lt;cntinfo&gt;
				&lt;cntperp&gt;
					&lt;cntper&gt;Steve Kloiber&lt;/cntper&gt;
					&lt;cntorg&gt;Metropolitan Council&lt;/cntorg&gt;
				&lt;/cntperp&gt;
				&lt;cntpos&gt;Environmental Analyst&lt;/cntpos&gt;
				&lt;cntaddr&gt;
					&lt;addrtype&gt; mailing and physical address &lt;/addrtype&gt;
					&lt;address&gt;390 Robert Street North&lt;/address&gt;
					&lt;city&gt;St. Paul&lt;/city&gt;
					&lt;state&gt;Minnesota&lt;/state&gt;
					&lt;postal&gt;55101-1805&lt;/postal&gt;
				&lt;/cntaddr&gt;
				&lt;cntvoice&gt;651-602-1056&lt;/cntvoice&gt;
				&lt;cntfax&gt;651-602-1130&lt;/cntfax&gt;
				&lt;cntemail&gt;steve.kloiber@metc.state.mn.us&lt;/cntemail&gt;
			&lt;/cntinfo&gt;
		&lt;/ptcontac&gt;
		&lt;browse&gt;
			&lt;browsen&gt;http://www.datafinder.org/metadata/SORRY_NO_SAMPLE_GRAPHIC_YET.htm&lt;/browsen&gt;
			&lt;browsed /&gt;
		&lt;/browse&gt;
		&lt;native&gt;ArcView database file&lt;/native&gt;
		&lt;crossref&gt;
			&lt;citeinfo&gt;
				&lt;title&gt;- Water Features from 2000 Land Use Data
- Natural Resource Inventory Table for Lakes and Large Rivers
- Streams Network Dissolved to Management Segments&lt;/title&gt;
			&lt;/citeinfo&gt;
		&lt;/crossref&gt;
	&lt;/idinfo&gt;
	&lt;dataqual&gt;
		&lt;attracc&gt;
			&lt;attraccr&gt;The attribute accuracy is dependent upon the accuracy of the source data and the method used to extract the source data and assign it to a given feature. No assessment of accuracy has been performed. Please refer to the Aquatic Resource Assessment Methods document for a discussion of the source data and the methods for additional information on attribute accuracy. Also, refer to the metadata for each source dataset listed in the methods document.&lt;/attraccr&gt;
		&lt;/attracc&gt;
		&lt;logic&gt;not applicable&lt;/logic&gt;
		&lt;complete&gt;Entire seven county geographic area is covered.&lt;/complete&gt;
		&lt;posacc&gt;
			&lt;horizpa&gt;
				&lt;horizpar&gt;not applicable&lt;/horizpar&gt;
			&lt;/horizpa&gt;
			&lt;vertacc&gt;
				&lt;vertaccr&gt;not applicable&lt;/vertaccr&gt;
			&lt;/vertacc&gt;
		&lt;/posacc&gt;
		&lt;lineage&gt;
			&lt;srcinfo&gt;
				&lt;srcscale /&gt;
			&lt;/srcinfo&gt;
			&lt;procstep&gt;
				&lt;procdesc&gt;The fields in this table provide descriptive information regarding the features contained in the stream_net_dslv dataset. Several of these fields were created by spatially joining other datasets such as parks, rare and endangered species, sites of biological significance, trout streams, and land cover to the strm_net_dslv dataset. Other data such as water supply information were obtained from hard copy documents and added to the table manually. After all required externally derived data were joined to the strm_net_dslv dataset, these additional fields were exported to this table and editted. Other fields representing the recreational importance and ecological importance were derived by applying criteria developed by the Metropolitan Council in consultation with several other agencies and organizations. Some field specific lineage information can be found in the attribute description section of this metadata. 

Please refer to the Aquatic Resource Assessment Report for further details (Metropolitan Council Publication 32-03-015). This document can be obtained online from  . . .&lt;/procdesc&gt;
			&lt;/procstep&gt;
		&lt;/lineage&gt;
	&lt;/dataqual&gt;
	&lt;spdoinfo&gt;
		&lt;indspref&gt;Stream ID&lt;/indspref&gt;
		&lt;direct /&gt;
		&lt;mgmg3obj /&gt;
		&lt;mgmg3til /&gt;
	&lt;/spdoinfo&gt;
	&lt;spref&gt;
		&lt;horizsys&gt;
			&lt;geograph&gt;
				&lt;latres /&gt;
				&lt;longres /&gt;
			&lt;/geograph&gt;
			&lt;planar&gt;
				&lt;mapproj&gt;
					&lt;mapprojn /&gt;
					&lt;mgmg4par /&gt;
					&lt;otherprj /&gt;
				&lt;/mapproj&gt;
				&lt;gridsys&gt;
					&lt;gridsysn /&gt;
					&lt;utm&gt;
						&lt;utmzone /&gt;
					&lt;/utm&gt;
					&lt;spcs&gt;
						&lt;spcszone /&gt;
					&lt;/spcs&gt;
					&lt;mgmg4coz /&gt;
					&lt;mgmg4adj /&gt;
				&lt;/gridsys&gt;
				&lt;planci&gt;
					&lt;coordrep&gt;
						&lt;absres /&gt;
						&lt;ordres /&gt;
					&lt;/coordrep&gt;
					&lt;distbrep&gt;
						&lt;distres /&gt;
					&lt;/distbrep&gt;
					&lt;plandu /&gt;
				&lt;/planci&gt;
			&lt;/planar&gt;
			&lt;geodetic&gt;
				&lt;horizdn /&gt;
				&lt;ellips /&gt;
			&lt;/geodetic&gt;
		&lt;/horizsys&gt;
		&lt;vertdef&gt;
			&lt;altsys&gt;
				&lt;altdatum /&gt;
				&lt;altunits /&gt;
			&lt;/altsys&gt;
			&lt;depthsys&gt;
				&lt;depthdn /&gt;
				&lt;depthdu /&gt;
			&lt;/depthsys&gt;
		&lt;/vertdef&gt;
	&lt;/spref&gt;
	&lt;eainfo&gt;
		&lt;overview&gt;
			&lt;eaover&gt;STREAM_ID:  A unique numeric identifier for each stream segment.  Stream 
            segments were aggregated from the digitized features of the 
            original source data layer.  Stream features were aggregated 
            according to Strahler stream order and connectivity.  Initially, 
            all stream features that had the same stream order and were 
            connected in an upstream-downstream relationship were aggregated 
            using an ArcInfo dissolve process.  Stream segements longer than 
            10,000 meters were then manually split at DNR minor watershed 
            boundaries.

SINUOSITY:  A measure of the channel sinuosity.  This is defined as the actual 
            stream length divided by the straight line distance from one end of 
            the segment to the other end. 

VERT_DENS:  The vertex density for each segment expressed as the number of 
            vertices per kilometer. 

GEOM_SCORE: A relative rank of the natural character of the stream geometry. 
            The value is a 1, 2, or 3, with a value of three being the most 
            natural geometry. 

RIP_VEG:    The fraction of the land area within 60 meters of the stream that 
            is covered by natural vegetation.  Values are expressed as real 
            numbers.

RIP_SCORE:  A relative rank based on the amount of natural vegetation in the 
            riparian zone based on the Rip_veg field.  The value is a 1, 2, or 
            3, with a value of three being the best natural vegetation cover. 

PHYS_SCORE: A relative rank of the physical condition of the stream for 
            ecological habitat.  The value is a 1, 2, or 3, with a value of 
            three being the best habitat condition. 

BIO_DIV:    Indicates whether a stream feature intersects a site of high 
            biodiversity as identified in the Minnesota County Biological 
            Survey (MCBS).  Values are Y or N.

TROUT:      Indicates whether any portion of a stream segment is a DNR 
            designated trout stream.  Values are Y or N.

NONMOBL_RE: The number of observations within the past 25 years, of rare, 
            endangered, threatened or unusual aquatic species (heretofore 
            referred to as R&amp;amp;E species) that are not mobile outside of an 
            aquatic environment (e.g. fish, mollusks, etc.) associated with a 
            stream segment. 

MBL_RE:     The number of observations within the past 25 years, of R&amp;amp;E species 
            that are mobile outside of an aquatic environment (e.g. reptiles, 
            birds, etc.) associated with stream segment feature. 

BIO_SCORE:  A relative score summarizing the known biologically significant 
            sites based on the Bio_div, Trout, Nonmbl_re, and Mble_re fields. 
            The value is a 1, 2, or 3, with a value of three having the highest 
            probability of important biological features. 

ECO_SCORE:  A relative rank of the overall ecological condition of the stream 
            segment based on the physical habitat condition and the known 
            probability of significant biological features.  The value is a 1, 
            2, or 3, with a value of three being the best overall ecological 
            condition. 

ADJ_PARK:   Indicates whether or not there is a public park adjacent to a 
            water feature.  Data for park locations was extracted from the 
            Metropolitan Council's 2000 land use dataset.  Values are Y or N.

CANOE_RT:   Indicates whether a stream segment is a State designated canoe 
            route.  Values are Y ro N.

FLOW_SCORE: A categorical flow rank (3, 2, or 1) based on the estimated median 
            summer flow.  Median summer flow is taken as an indicator of the 
            ability of a stream or river to support contact recreation.  A 
            higher score indicates a higher relative rank by median summer 
            flow.

REC_SCORE:  A relative score summarizing the regional recreational significance 
            based on the Flow_score and Adj_park fields.  The value is a 1, 2, 
            or 3, with a value of three being more regionally important for 
            recreational use.&lt;/eaover&gt;
			&lt;eadetcit&gt;Data were developed by the Metropolitan Council with input from several other agencies and organizations. Please refer to the Aquatic Resource Assessment Report for further details (Metropolitan Council Publication 32-03-015). This document can be obtained online at  http://www.metrocouncil.org/planning/environment/ara_report.pdf .&lt;/eadetcit&gt;
		&lt;/overview&gt;
	&lt;/eainfo&gt;
	&lt;distinfo&gt;
		&lt;distrib&gt;
			&lt;cntinfo&gt;
				&lt;cntperp&gt;
					&lt;cntper&gt;Mark Kotz&lt;/cntper&gt;
					&lt;cntorg&gt;Metropolitan Council&lt;/cntorg&gt;
				&lt;/cntperp&gt;
				&lt;cntpos&gt;GIS Database Administrator&lt;/cntpos&gt;
				&lt;cntaddr&gt;
					&lt;addrtype&gt; mailing and physical address &lt;/addrtype&gt;
					&lt;address&gt;390 Robert Street North&lt;/address&gt;
					&lt;city&gt;St. Paul&lt;/city&gt;
					&lt;state&gt;Minnesota&lt;/state&gt;
					&lt;postal&gt;55101-1805&lt;/postal&gt;
				&lt;/cntaddr&gt;
				&lt;cntvoice&gt;651-602-1644&lt;/cntvoice&gt;
				&lt;cntfax&gt;651-602-1674&lt;/cntfax&gt;
				&lt;cntemail&gt;mark.kotz@metc.state.mn.us&lt;/cntemail&gt;
			&lt;/cntinfo&gt;
		&lt;/distrib&gt;
		&lt;resdesc&gt;NRIAStreamsNetworkTable&lt;/resdesc&gt;
		&lt;distliab&gt;NOTICE:  The Geographic Information System (GIS) Data to which this notice is attached are made available pursuant to the Minnesota Government Data Practices Act (Minnesota Statutes Chapter 13).  THE GIS DATA ARE PROVIDED TO YOU AS IS AND WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY AS TO THEIR PERFORMANCE, MERCHANTABILITY, OR FITNESS FOR ANY PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  The GIS Data were developed by the Metropolitan Council for its own internal business purposes.  The Metropolitan Council does not represent or warrant that the GIS Data or the data documentation are error-free, complete, current, or accurate.  You are responsible for any consequences resulting from your use of the GIS Data or your reliance on the GIS Data.  You should consult the data documentation for this particular GIS Data to determine the limitations of the GIS Data and the precision with which the GIS Data may depict distance, direction, location, or other geographic features.  If you transmit or provide the GIS Data (or any portion of it) to another user, it is recommended that the GIS Data include a copy of this disclaimer and this metadata.&lt;/distliab&gt;
		&lt;stdorder&gt;
			&lt;digform&gt;
				&lt;digtinfo&gt;
					&lt;formname&gt;dBase&lt;/formname&gt;
					&lt;formvern&gt;IV&lt;/formvern&gt;
					&lt;transize&gt;Less than 1 MB for zip file.&lt;/transize&gt;
				&lt;/digtinfo&gt;
			&lt;/digform&gt;
			&lt;ordering&gt;This dataset is distributed on the internet by clicking below after 'Online Linkage'.  Doing so will tell your browser to download a 'ZIP' file which will contain the following:

- dBase files
- metadata for the dataset (.htm)
- NOTICE.RTF, an important notice about this dataset that can be read by any word processing software.

 &lt;/ordering&gt;
		&lt;/stdorder&gt;
	&lt;/distinfo&gt;
	&lt;metainfo&gt;
		&lt;metd&gt;20030410&lt;/metd&gt;
		&lt;metc&gt;
			&lt;cntinfo&gt;
				&lt;cntperp&gt;
					&lt;cntper&gt;Steve Kloiber&lt;/cntper&gt;
					&lt;cntorg&gt;Metropolitan Council&lt;/cntorg&gt;
				&lt;/cntperp&gt;
				&lt;cntpos&gt;Environmental Analyst&lt;/cntpos&gt;
				&lt;cntaddr&gt;
					&lt;addrtype&gt; mailing and physical address &lt;/addrtype&gt;
					&lt;address&gt;390 Robert Street North&lt;/address&gt;
					&lt;city&gt;St. Paul&lt;/city&gt;
					&lt;state&gt;Minnesota&lt;/state&gt;
					&lt;postal&gt;55101-1805&lt;/postal&gt;
				&lt;/cntaddr&gt;
				&lt;cntvoice&gt;651-602-1056&lt;/cntvoice&gt;
				&lt;cntfax&gt;651-602-1130&lt;/cntfax&gt;
				&lt;cntemail&gt;steve.kloiber@metc.state.mn.us&lt;/cntemail&gt;
			&lt;/cntinfo&gt;
		&lt;/metc&gt;
		&lt;metstdn&gt;Minnesota Geographic Metadata Guidelines&lt;/metstdn&gt;
		&lt;metstdv&gt;1.2&lt;/metstdv&gt;
		&lt;metextns&gt;
			&lt;onlink&gt;http://www.gis.state.mn.us/stds/metadata.htm&lt;/onlink&gt;
		&lt;/metextns&gt;
	&lt;/metainfo&gt;
	&lt;Esri&gt;&lt;ModDate&gt;20040920&lt;/ModDate&gt;&lt;ModTime&gt;09550800&lt;/ModTime&gt;&lt;/Esri&gt;&lt;mdDateSt Sync="TRUE"&gt;20040920&lt;/mdDateSt&gt;&lt;/metadata&gt;</field></doc></add>