<add allowDups="false"><doc><field name="LayerId">TransitStops</field><field name="Name">17</field><field name="CollectionId">initial collection</field><field name="Institution">Minnesota</field><field name="InstitutionSort">Minnesota</field><field name="Access">Public</field><field name="DataType">Undefined</field><field name="DataTypeSort">Undefined</field><field name="Availability">Online</field><field name="LayerDisplayName">Transit Stops</field><field name="LayerDisplayNameSort">Transit Stops</field><field name="Publisher">Metropolitan Council - Metro Transit</field><field name="PublisherSort">Metropolitan Council - Metro Transit</field><field name="Originator">Metropolitan Council - Metro Transit</field><field name="OriginatorSort">Metropolitan Council - Metro Transit</field><field name="ThemeKeywords">None</field><field name="PlaceKeywords">None</field><field name="Abstract">The Transit Stops layer contains over 18,000 active and inactive transit stops in the Twin Cities seven county metropolitan area.  Stops where boarding and/or alighing occurs are flagged in the busstop_yn field.

The dataset includes attributes from the primary transit stop database maintained for Metro Transit and for customer information for other transit provider transit services.  The locations are mapped referencing NCompass Technologies Inc. street centerline network along with streets generated internally at Metro Transit.  </field><field name="MaxY">45.415</field><field name="MinY">44.471</field><field name="MinX">-94.012</field><field name="MaxX">-92.732</field><field name="ContentDate">2013-06-24T00:00:00Z</field><field name="Location">{"download": "ftp://gisftp.metc.state.mn.us/TransitStops.zip", "ArcGISRest": "http://gis2.metc.state.mn.us/ArcGIS/rest/services/MetroGIS/Transportation/MapServer/export"}</field><field name="WorkspaceName" /><field name="FgdcText">&lt;?xml version="1.0"?&gt;&lt;metadata&gt;&lt;idinfo&gt;&lt;citation&gt;&lt;citeinfo&gt;&lt;origin&gt;Metropolitan Council - Metro Transit&lt;/origin&gt;&lt;pubinfo&gt;&lt;publish&gt;Metropolitan Council - Metro Transit&lt;/publish&gt;&lt;/pubinfo&gt;&lt;pubdate&gt;20120123&lt;/pubdate&gt;&lt;title&gt;Transit Stops&lt;/title&gt;&lt;onlink&gt;ftp://gisftp.metc.state.mn.us/TransitStops.zip&lt;/onlink&gt;&lt;/citeinfo&gt;&lt;/citation&gt;&lt;descript&gt;&lt;abstract&gt;The Transit Stops layer contains over 18,000 active and inactive transit stops in the Twin Cities seven county metropolitan area.  Stops where boarding and/or alighing occurs are flagged in the busstop_yn field.

The dataset includes attributes from the primary transit stop database maintained for Metro Transit and for customer information for other transit provider transit services.  The locations are mapped referencing NCompass Technologies Inc. street centerline network along with streets generated internally at Metro Transit.  &lt;/abstract&gt;&lt;purpose&gt;To identify all stop locations in the Twin Cities metropolitan area where transit service exists. &lt;/purpose&gt;&lt;supplinf&gt;Twin Cities 7 county metropolitan area.  This includes the counties of Anoka, Carver, Dakota, Hennepin, Ramsey, Scott and Washington.&lt;/supplinf&gt;&lt;/descript&gt;&lt;browse&gt;&lt;browsen&gt;none available&lt;/browsen&gt;&lt;/browse&gt;&lt;timeperd&gt;&lt;current&gt;Bus Stop information is updated weekly&lt;/current&gt;&lt;/timeperd&gt;&lt;status&gt;&lt;progress&gt;Complete&lt;/progress&gt;&lt;update&gt;Weekly&lt;/update&gt;&lt;/status&gt;&lt;spdom&gt;&lt;bounding&gt;&lt;westbc&gt;-94.012&lt;/westbc&gt;&lt;eastbc&gt;-92.732&lt;/eastbc&gt;&lt;northbc&gt;45.415&lt;/northbc&gt;&lt;southbc&gt;44.471&lt;/southbc&gt;&lt;/bounding&gt;&lt;/spdom&gt;&lt;keywords&gt;&lt;place&gt;&lt;placekey&gt;Twin Cities, Anoka County, Carver County, Dakota County, Hennepin County, Ramsey County, Scott County, Washington County &lt;/placekey&gt;&lt;/place&gt;&lt;theme&gt;&lt;themekey&gt;transit, buses, bus stops, transportation&lt;/themekey&gt;&lt;/theme&gt;&lt;/keywords&gt;&lt;crossref&gt;&lt;citeinfo&gt;&lt;title&gt;bus routes, bus segments, bus service, bus shelters, park &amp;amp; rides. 
For information comparing the different transit GIS datasets distributed by the Met. Council, please see http://www.datafinder.org/metadata/transit_data_overview.pdf
&lt;/title&gt;&lt;/citeinfo&gt;&lt;/crossref&gt;&lt;accconst&gt;None&lt;/accconst&gt;&lt;useconst&gt;None&lt;/useconst&gt;&lt;ptcontac&gt;&lt;cntinfo&gt;&lt;cntperp&gt;&lt;cntorg&gt;Metropolitan Council - Metro Transit&lt;/cntorg&gt;&lt;cntper&gt;Steve Baisden&lt;/cntper&gt;&lt;/cntperp&gt;&lt;cntpos&gt;Associate Planner&lt;/cntpos&gt;&lt;cntaddr&gt;&lt;address&gt;560 6th Ave N&lt;/address&gt;&lt;city&gt;Minneapolis&lt;/city&gt;&lt;state&gt;MN&lt;/state&gt;&lt;postal&gt;55411&lt;/postal&gt;&lt;/cntaddr&gt;&lt;cntvoice&gt;612.349.7361&lt;/cntvoice&gt;&lt;cntemail&gt;stephen.baisden@metrotransit.org&lt;/cntemail&gt;&lt;/cntinfo&gt;&lt;/ptcontac&gt;&lt;/idinfo&gt;&lt;dataqual&gt;&lt;attracc&gt;&lt;attraccr&gt;Attributes randomly checked by Metro Transit staff.&lt;/attraccr&gt;&lt;/attracc&gt;&lt;complete&gt;All active and inactive transit stops.&lt;/complete&gt;&lt;posacc&gt;&lt;horizpa&gt;&lt;horizpar&gt;Positional accuracy reflects stops and their association with the street centerline network. &lt;/horizpar&gt;&lt;/horizpa&gt;&lt;/posacc&gt;&lt;/dataqual&gt;&lt;distinfo&gt;&lt;distliab&gt;NOTICE:  The Geographic Information System (GIS) Data to which this notice is attached are made available pursuant to the Minnesota Government Data Practices Act (Minnesota Statutes Chapter 13).  THE GIS DATA ARE PROVIDED TO YOU AS IS AND WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY AS TO THEIR PERFORMANCE, MERCHANTABILITY, OR FITNESS FOR ANY PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  The GIS Data were developed by the Metropolitan Council for its own internal business purposes.  The Metropolitan Council does not represent or warrant that the GIS Data or the data documentation are error-free, complete, current, or accurate.  You are responsible for any consequences resulting from your use of the GIS Data or your reliance on the GIS Data.  You should consult the data documentation for this particular GIS Data to determine the limitations of the GIS Data and the precision with which the GIS Data may depict distance, direction, location, or other geographic features.  If you transmit or provide the GIS Data (or any portion of it) to another user, it is recommended that the GIS Data include a copy of this disclaimer and this metadata.&lt;/distliab&gt;&lt;stdorder&gt;&lt;ordering&gt;This dataset is distributed on the internet by clicking below after 'Online Linkage'.  Doing so will tell your browser to download a 'ZIP' file which will contain the following:

- ArcView shape files
- metadata for the dataset (.htm)
- NOTICE.RTF, an important notice about this datasett that can be read by any word processing software.

Additionally, this dataset is available for direct use via one or more map services.  More information about what a map service is can be found at http://www.datafinder.org/services/.  The specific map service and layer name for this dataset can be found by clicking the "Services" link for this dataset in the DataFinder Catalog at http://www.datafinder.org/catalog/ .&lt;/ordering&gt;&lt;/stdorder&gt;&lt;distrib&gt;&lt;cntinfo&gt;&lt;cntperp&gt;&lt;cntorg&gt;Metropolitan Council&lt;/cntorg&gt;&lt;cntper&gt;Jon Hoekenga&lt;/cntper&gt;&lt;/cntperp&gt;&lt;cntpos&gt;GIS System Administrator&lt;/cntpos&gt;&lt;cntaddr&gt;&lt;address&gt;390 Robert Street North&lt;/address&gt;&lt;city&gt;St. Paul&lt;/city&gt;&lt;state&gt;MN&lt;/state&gt;&lt;postal&gt;55101-1805&lt;/postal&gt;&lt;/cntaddr&gt;&lt;cntvoice&gt;651.602.1561&lt;/cntvoice&gt;&lt;cntemail&gt;jonathan.hoekenga@metc.state.mn.us&lt;/cntemail&gt;&lt;/cntinfo&gt;&lt;/distrib&gt;&lt;/distinfo&gt;&lt;metainfo&gt;&lt;metd&gt;20120123&lt;/metd&gt;&lt;metstdn&gt;Minnesota Geographic Metadata Guidelines&lt;/metstdn&gt;&lt;metstdv&gt;1.2&lt;/metstdv&gt;&lt;metextns&gt;&lt;onlink&gt;http://www.mngeo.state.mn.us/committee/standards/mgmg/metadata.htm&lt;/onlink&gt;&lt;/metextns&gt;&lt;metc&gt;&lt;cntinfo&gt;&lt;cntperp&gt;&lt;cntorg&gt;Metropolitan Council - Metro Transit&lt;/cntorg&gt;&lt;cntper&gt;Steve Baisden&lt;/cntper&gt;&lt;/cntperp&gt;&lt;cntpos&gt;Associate Planner&lt;/cntpos&gt;&lt;cntaddr&gt;&lt;address&gt;560 6th Ave N&lt;/address&gt;&lt;city&gt;Minneapolis&lt;/city&gt;&lt;state&gt;MN&lt;/state&gt;&lt;postal&gt;55411&lt;/postal&gt;&lt;/cntaddr&gt;&lt;cntvoice&gt;612.349.7361&lt;/cntvoice&gt;&lt;cntemail&gt;stephen.baisden@metrotransit.org&lt;/cntemail&gt;&lt;/cntinfo&gt;&lt;/metc&gt;&lt;/metainfo&gt;&lt;eainfo&gt;&lt;overview&gt;&lt;eaover&gt;side_id:  The primary key field and unique stop identification number assigned by Metro Transit. 

site_on:  The street or address where the stop is found. 

site_at:  The cross street or address nearest the stop. 

corn_desc:  The description of the corner the bus stop is on.

city:  The city the stop is located in. 

county: The county where the stop is located in

publiccomm:  Miscellaneous oomments about the stop.

dt_zone:  The stop is part of the 50-cent Downtown Fare Zone.

bench:  Indicates if a bench is located at a stop (1)

parkride:  The bus stop is at a park &amp;amp; ride.

sidewalk:  A sidewalk exists at the stop.

adaaccess:  The stop has a firm surface.
 
ada_comm:  A description of whether obstacles in the field potentially inhibit boarding and/alighting.

busstop_yn: Indicates whether boarding and alighting may occur at a stop.
 
node_id:  For those sites that are nodes, this field contains their four letter identification.  Nodes are often timepoints, or places where the bus has to arrive/depart at a certain time.  Note, however, that more than one site can have the same Nodeid because a route will use different sites in different directions. 

sign:  A transit stop sign exists at the location.  By default stops are flagged as having them unless noted otherwise.  

shelter: A shelter exists at the stop.
 
hi_freq:  Stop is part of the Hi-Frequency Network and receives special signage.  These stops are served by a route every 15 minutes or better on weekdays from 6AM-7PM and Saturdays 9AM-6PM. 

street_id:   The street identification number the stop is localized on.  Numbers match the NCompass Technologies Inc. street centerline file or streets generated in HASTUS scheduling software.

gate:  The gate letter or number used for distinguishing stops at specific areas.&lt;/eaover&gt;&lt;/overview&gt;&lt;/eainfo&gt;&lt;spref&gt;&lt;horizsys&gt;&lt;planar&gt;&lt;gridsys&gt;&lt;gridsysn&gt;Universal Transverse Mercator&lt;/gridsysn&gt;&lt;utm&gt;&lt;utmzone&gt;15&lt;/utmzone&gt;&lt;/utm&gt;&lt;/gridsys&gt;&lt;planci&gt;&lt;plandu&gt;meters&lt;/plandu&gt;&lt;/planci&gt;&lt;/planar&gt;&lt;geodetic&gt;&lt;horizdn&gt;NAD83&lt;/horizdn&gt;&lt;ellips&gt;GRS80&lt;/ellips&gt;&lt;/geodetic&gt;&lt;/horizsys&gt;&lt;/spref&gt;&lt;/metadata&gt;</field></doc></add>